Guide to the French Communist Party poster collection, 1949-2008
George Mason University Libraries
- Series 2: Social Posters, 1950-2008; (Box 6, Shelf 5, MC)
  - Subseries 2.3: Meetings, Programs, and Television Appearances, 1950-2006; (Box 6, Shelf 5, MC)
    - Meetings and Programs, 1958-2000, undated (Oversize Shelf 5, Folder 3)
      5 roughly 35x45cm, 18 roughly 60x80cm, 4 roughly 40x100cm, 15 70x100cm, 1 100x140cm, 2 30x80cm, 1 120x160cm, 3 50x70cm, and 1 17x50cm sized posters; poster topics include large public meetings, large parties, regional debates, television appearances, and student and young worker meetings, as well as meetings with top party leaders to discuss various party issues.
    - Women, Protests, Congresses and Meetings, 1950?-1980, undated (Oversize MC, Folder 3)
      5 40x120cm, 1 76x102cm, and 16 80x120cm sized posters; meetings include those with top leaders of the party, with Marchais, and with women, topics include petrol, the Front Populare, Christmas programs, and referendums.
  - Subseries 2.4: Protests, 1954?-2008; (Shelf 5, MC)
    Subseries 2.4 contains posters that advertise for protest marches.
    - Protests, 1959-2008 (Oversize Shelf 5, Folder 4)
      8 roughly 60x80cm, 4 roughly 30x100cm, 2 roughly 45x60cm, 1 35x48cm, and 2 70x100cm sized posters; poster topics include secular schools, the youth against apartheid and Giscard, protests against nuclear weapons and the Front National, and protests for jobs and salaries.
    - Women, Protests, Congresses and Meetings, 1954?-1968 (Oversize MC, Folder 3)
      1 40x120cm and 1 80x120cm sized posters; one poster is for a protest in honor of the founder of l'Humanité and the other for the commune of Paris.
  - Subseries 2.5: Congresses, Vente-Expositions, and Fêtes de l'Humanité, 1957-2007; (Box 6, Shelf 5, MC)
    Subseries 2.5 contains posters to advertise and celebrate for Congresses, Vente-exposition, and the Fête de l'Humanité. Congresses and Fetes are annual gatherings of party members, similar to a convention or festival. Vente-Expositions are book festivals.
    - Congress and fête de l'humanité, 1959-1985 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      5 40x60cm posters; one poster advertises the 15th Congress and the other four show facsimiles of old posters for the 1985 fête de l'humanité.
    - Vente-Exposition, 1959-1991 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      6 roughly 39x59cm, 1 32x50cm, 3 28x39cm, 1 35x44cm, 1 64x50cm, 1 68x47cm, and 1 46x61cm sized posters; posters advertise Vente-Expositions for Marxist books, the history of the PCF, art and books, the anniversary of the Paris commune, a Grand Gala du lien, a technology expo, and a night of cinema.
    - Vente-Expositions/Congress, 1959-2000 (Oversize Shelf 5, Folder 5)
      13 roughly 60x80cm, 7 roughly 60x100cm, 1 35x70cm, and 2 roughly 40x80cm sized posters; topics include expositions for Soviet or Marxist books, music celebrations, and Congresses.
    - Fête de l'humanité, 1973-2007 (Oversize Shelf 5, Folder 6)
      9 70x100cm, 1 55x75cm, 1 33x48cm, 1 49x65cm, 1 40x60cm, 1 47x58cm, 2 60x80cm, and 1 34x100cm sized posters advertising for the Fête de l'humanité.
    - Women, Protests, Congresses and Meetings, 1957-1976 (Oversize MC, Folder 3)
      1 40x120cm and 7 80x120cm sized posters; topics include Congresses and Marxist book celebrations.
  - Subseries 2.6: Publications, 1958-2001; (Box 6, Shelf 5, MC)
    Subseries 2.6 contains posters to advertise for Communist publications, including book releases by party members and newspapers or journals published by the French Communist Party.
    - Publications, 1958-2001 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      2 30x40cm, 3 roughly 59x39cm, 1 52x38cm, 2 69x48cm, and 1 35x5cm sized posters; the publication advertised include L'Humanité, France Nouvelle, Marchais's L'Espoir au Present, Economie et Politique, Avancées, and Communistes.
    - Publications, 1973?-2001 (Oversize Shelf 5, Folder 6)
      6 40x60cm, 12 60x80cm, and 1 70x100cm sized posters; topics include the newspapers L'Humanité, Economie et Politique, and Les Espaces Citoyens; Marchais's books Le Defi Democratique and Espoir au Present; Robert Hue's Communisme: La Mutation; and nights of cinema.
    - Commemorative and Publications, 1973-1980, undated (Oversize MC, Folder 4)
      3 40x120cm and 3 80x120cm sized posters; publications include the book for the Fête de l'Humanité, Le Patriote newspaper, and Marchais's L'Espoir au Present and Le Defi Democratique.